<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate Change on </title>
    <link>/zh/tags/climate-change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Climate Change on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/zh/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrologic modeling in project HYPERION</title>
      <link>/zh/research/hyperion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/research/hyperion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction of HYPERION  The objective of HYPERION is the development of a comprehensive regional hydroclimate data assessment capability focused on feature-specific metrics and stakeholder-relevant outcomes. The secondary objective of this proposal is to leverage this assessment capability to improve our ability to predict these outcomes, by identifying the process-level drivers of outcome biases and evaluating the most appropriate and efficient ways to couple climate models, hydrologic models, and models of human impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake-PIHM modeling in CNH-Lake project</title>
      <link>/zh/research/cnh_lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/research/cnh_lak/</guid>
      <description>This project is the hydrology-lake modeling part of the whole project. The leading project is CNH-L: Linking land-use decision making, water quality, and lake associations to understand human-natural feedbacks in lake catchments, cooperated with multiple universities and institutes(e.g. Virginia Tech, Pennsylvania State University, University of Wisconsin, Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies, Michigan State University ).
Introduction of project  Freshwater lakes and their catchments present a rich and fascinating opportunity to examine the dynamics of coupled natural and human systems (CNHS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the role of landuse change on water yield at the Maya urban</title>
      <link>/zh/research/tikal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/research/tikal/</guid>
      <description>This project is the hydrology-lake modeling part of the project Land, Water, and Territory: A 3,000-Year Study of Niche Construction and Cultural Evolution in the Tikal National Park, Guatemala. The view in Tikal 
Introduction of project Location of Tikal  ## Tasks in hydrologic modeling Land use map of Tikal  Elevation of Tikal 
Accomplishment of the project keep updating</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catchment hydrological change from soil degradation</title>
      <link>/zh/talk/agu2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/talk/agu2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the role of landuse change on water yield at the Maya urban center Tikal, Guatemala [700-800 AD]</title>
      <link>/zh/talk/agu2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/talk/agu2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>