<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | SHU</title>
    <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.shulele.net/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid stigmatizing names for 2019 novel coronavirus</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2020nature_covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2020nature_covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus that is currently causing severe respiratory illness worldwide has now been named SARS-CoV-2, and the disease is COVID-19. When the virus first emerged last December, it was generally described in medical journals as the ‘2019 novel coronavirus’. Nature, however, used ‘China coronavirus’ and ‘Wuhan coronavirus’. Such interim terminology based on geographic characteristics is objectionable because it can stimulate prejudice and discrimination against Chinese people, fuelled internationally by fear spread through social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it is difficult and time-consuming to formally name diseases and viruses, it is essential that we methodically select no-harm names for them to make their way into human history. In 2015, the World Health Organization issued guidelines intended to minimize “unnecessary negative impact of disease names on trade, travel, tourism or animal welfare, and avoid causing offence to any cultural, social, national, regional, professional or ethnic groups”. It asks scientists, journalists and health officials to use neutral, generic terms when referring to new human infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor’s note&lt;/strong&gt;: Nature has stopped referring to the 2019 novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) as the Wuhan or China virus, for the reasons cited in the Correspondence. The names that appeared in earlier headlines were used to reflect the situation as it was understood at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature 578, 363 (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solver for Hydrologic Unstructured Domain (SHUD): Numerical modeling of watershed hydrology with the finite volume method</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2019shu_shud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2019shu_shud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hydrological modeling is an essential strategy for understanding natural flows, particularly where observations are lacking in either space or time, or where topographic roughness leads to a disconnect in the characteristic timescales of overland and groundwater flow. Consequently, significant opportunities remain for the development of extensible modeling systems that operate robustly across regions.
Towards the development of such a robust hydrological modeling system, this paper introduces the Solver for Hydrological Unstructured Domain (SHUD), an integrated multi-process, multi-scale, multi-timestep hydrological model, in which hydrological processes are fully coupled using the semi-discrete Finite Volume Method. The SHUD integrates overland flow, snow accumulation/melting, evapotranspiration, subsurface and groundwater flow, and river routing, while realistically capturing the physical processes in a watershed.&lt;br /&gt;
The SHUD incorporates one-dimension unsaturated flow, two-dimension groundwater flow, and river channels connected with hillslopes via overland flow and baseflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces the design of SHUD, from the conceptual and mathematical description of hydrological processes in a watershed to computational structures. To demonstrate and validate the model performance, we employ three hydrological experiments: the V-Catchment experiment, Vauclin&amp;rsquo;s experiment, and a study of the Cache Creek Watershed in northern California, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible applications of then SHUD model include hydrological studies from the hillslope scale to regional scale, water resource and stormwater management, and coupling research with related fields such as limnology, agriculture, geochemistry, geomorphology, water quality, and ecology, climatic and landuse change.  In general, SHUD is a valuable scientific tool for any modeling task involving simulating and understanding hydrological response.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China’s different shades of greening</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2019nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2019nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your view that China’s re-vegetation of its deserts could exacerbate water shortages risks oversimplifying an incredibly complex eco-restoration problem (Nature 573, 474–475; 2019).
Far from just planting trees in arid areas, China’s re-vegetation codes vary for different regions and greening programmes. The nationwide Grain-to-Green programme, for example, aims to restore unstable and low-productivity farmlands to forest or natural vegetation. In humid areas, research optimizes greening programmes for plant selection and socio- economic benefits. And China’s re-vegetation projects are confined to a range that local water resources can sustain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-vegetation, like any eco-restoration strategy, is not a catch-all solution to carbon sequestration, soil erosion and flooding. But, rather than worrying mainly about water consumption, Chinese and other scientists are investigating the nexus of vegetation, soil, water, ecosystems and human society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature 577, 29 (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating fast and slow processes is essential for simulating human–freshwater interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2018ward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2018ward/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From concept to practice to policy: modeling coupled natural and human systems in lake catchments</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2018cobourn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2018cobourn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Urbanization and Climate Change on the Hydrological Cycle: A Study in Modern and Ancient Land Use Change</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2017shu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2017shu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated modeling environment and a preliminary application on the Heihe River Basin, China</title>
      <link>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2011nan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.shulele.net/en/publication/2011nan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
