<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PIHM on Lele&#39;s Page</title>
    <link>/tags/pihm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PIHM on Lele&#39;s Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pihm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Model simulated spatial distribution and the variation of ground water level in Sacramento Watershed, California from 1985 to 2017</title>
      <link>/talk/agu2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/agu2018/</guid>
      <description>Annual Precipitation (1985-2017) of Sacramento Watershed  Please stop by my poster, we can have a talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic hydrologic deployment and modeling</title>
      <link>/research/mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/mint/</guid>
      <description>This project is the hydrologic modeling part of the project Model Integration through Knowledge-Rich Data and Process Composition.
Introduction of project  Tasks in hydrologic modeling The completed workflow of hydrologic modeling with PIHM model and national/global data services.   Animation of flood plant in South Sudan from 2001 to 2017 based on FLDAS data.   Accomplishment of the project keep updating</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Cellular Automata Land Use Change with Distributed Hydrologic models</title>
      <link>/talk/agu2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/agu2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake-PIHM modeling in CNH-Lake project</title>
      <link>/research/cnh_lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/cnh_lak/</guid>
      <description>This project is the hydrology-lake modeling part of the whole project. The leading project is CNH-L: Linking land-use decision making, water quality, and lake associations to understand human-natural feedbacks in lake catchments, cooperated with multiple universities and institutes(e.g. Virginia Tech, Pennsylvania State University, University of Wisconsin, Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies, Michigan State University ).
Introduction of project  Freshwater lakes and their catchments present a rich and fascinating opportunity to examine the dynamics of coupled natural and human systems (CNHS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the role of landuse change on water yield at the Maya urban</title>
      <link>/research/tikal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/tikal/</guid>
      <description>This project is the hydrology-lake modeling part of the project Land, Water, and Territory: A 3,000-Year Study of Niche Construction and Cultural Evolution in the Tikal National Park, Guatemala. The view in Tikal 
Introduction of project Location of Tikal  ## Tasks in hydrologic modeling Land use map of Tikal  Elevation of Tikal 
Accomplishment of the project keep updating</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catchment hydrological change from soil degradation</title>
      <link>/talk/agu2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/agu2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact in hydrology from landuse and climate change</title>
      <link>/research/stormwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/stormwater/</guid>
      <description>This project is the hydrologic modeling part of the project NSF Hydrologic and Water Quality Modeling for Green Infrastructure. Overview of the use of artificial intelligence techniques to support model integration 
Overview of the use of artificial intelligence techniques to support model integration  Introduction of project Tasks in hydrologic modeling  Elevation and PIHM mesh of the Pongo watershed in South Sudan   Accomplishment of the project keep updating</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the role of landuse change on water yield at the Maya urban center Tikal, Guatemala [700-800 AD]</title>
      <link>/talk/agu2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/agu2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urbanization-driven hydrological process change in Conestoga River watershed in Lancaster of Pennsylvania</title>
      <link>/talk/agu2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/agu2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>