<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lele Shu&#39;s Page</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lele Shu&#39;s Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:15:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 10 03 R Script to Animate Global Ndvi</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-03-r-script-to-animate-global-ndvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:15:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-03-r-script-to-animate-global-ndvi/</guid>
      <description>This script is to demonstrate the capability and scheme to realise the animation. You have to prepare your own data for this animation script. Script for Global NDVI rm(list=ls()) library(RoundAndRound) # devtools::install_github(&#39;shulele/RoundAndRound&#39;) col.fun=function(x){ colorspace::terrain_hcl(x, l=c(65,95), power=c(1/3, 1.5)) } plotStar &amp;lt;- function(x, y, radius, angle=180, xyratio=1, ...){ i &amp;lt;- 1:11 alpha &amp;lt;- 2*pi / 10 r &amp;lt;- radius * (i %% 2 + 1)/2 omega &amp;lt;- alpha * i + angle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monthly NDVI change in USA and Global from 2002-2017</title>
      <link>/post/monthly-ndvi-change-in-china-usa-and-global-from-2002-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/monthly-ndvi-change-in-china-usa-and-global-from-2002-2017/</guid>
      <description>Global NDVI
 The normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) is a simple graphical indicator that reflect the greenness and the heath condition of vegetations.
The raw data is from NASA MOD13A.
 The global NDVI variation from 2002 to 2017. 
 The NDVI varies from 2002 to 2017 in US (Continental) 
  How to download the rawdata The code of the monthly NDVI from MODIS dataset is MOD13C2, so type the code below in your terminal and the wget will download all availalble data from server to you local matchine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The explanation of Bayesian Theorem in Statistics</title>
      <link>/post/the-explanation-of-bayesian-theorem-in-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-explanation-of-bayesian-theorem-in-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian probability Inference Educated guessing
Thomas Bayes A nonconformist; two books, about theology and probability.
Bayesian inference Guessing the probability in the style of Bayes
Bayesian probability also known as evidential probability, is the process of adding prior probability to a hypothesis and adjusting that probability as new information becomes available. Unlike traditional frequentist probability which only accounts for the previous frequency of an event to predicate and outcome, the Bayesian model begins with an initial set of subjective assumptions (prior probability) and adjusts them accordingly through trial and experimentation (posterior probability).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The project to plot planets/objects in space and orbital movement.</title>
      <link>/post/roundandround/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/roundandround/</guid>
      <description>I planed to write an R package and submit on CRAN, that can plot the planets orbiting in Solar System, or satellite/moon orbiting around earth. That package must plot the moving planets, the moon, moon phase and satellite in 2D or 3D canvas. In future, it may calculate the orbit based on orbit mechanics.
My son loves the song “The wheels on the bus go round and round“, and he has an obsession on planets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The project to plot planets/objects in space and orbital movement.</title>
      <link>/post/kids-ucd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kids-ucd/</guid>
      <description>Motivation of the project This is fantastic program to teach the local kids and lead them into the discovering sciences.
 Panoview of the Math&amp;Science classroom.  Week 02: Week 03: Jessica is writing students observation and discussion of plants in two different soils (Sperpentine and sandy loam).   Week 05: Week 05: The growth condition of their beans.  Week 05: One question from students&#39; question box. Question: Why are my plants leaves sticky?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-02-r-code-to-animate-the-spatial-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-02-r-code-to-animate-the-spatial-change/</guid>
      <description>+++ title = “2019 10 02 R: Animate the Spatial data (global NDVI)” date = 2019-10-02T16:38:21-07:00 draft = false
Tags and categories  For example, use tags = [] for no tags, or the form tags = [&amp;quot;A Tag&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Another Tag&amp;quot;] for one or more tags. tags = [“NDVI”] categories = [“post”]
 Featured image  To use, add an image named featured.jpg/png to your page’s folder. [image] # Caption (optional) caption = “”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>