<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/zh/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 23:37:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/zh/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 10 02 R Animate the Global Spatial Data Ndvi</title>
      <link>/zh/post/2019-10-02-r-animate-the-global-spatial-data-ndvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 23:37:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/post/2019-10-02-r-animate-the-global-spatial-data-ndvi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monthly NDVI change in USA and Global from 2002-2017</title>
      <link>/zh/post/monthly-ndvi-change-in-china-usa-and-global-from-2002-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/post/monthly-ndvi-change-in-china-usa-and-global-from-2002-2017/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-06-27-monthly-ndvi-change-in-china-usa-and-global-from-2002-2017_files/NDVI.png&#34; alt=&#34;Global NDVI&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Global NDVI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) is a simple graphical indicator that reflect the greenness and the heath condition of vegetations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The raw data is from &lt;a href=&#34;https://modis.gsfc.nasa.gov/data/dataprod/mod13.php&#34;&gt;NASA MOD13A&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The global NDVI variation from 2002 to 2017. &lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7yyPfozr1PU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NDVI varies from 2002 to 2017 in US (Continental) &lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LL0qRwLLd1g&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-to-download-the-rawdata&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to download the rawdata&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code of the monthly NDVI from MODIS dataset is MOD13C2, so type the code below in your terminal and the wget will download all availalble data from server to you local matchine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget  --user=XXXXX --password=XXXX -r -c -np -x https://e4ftl01.cr.usgs.gov/MOLT/MOD13C2.006/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The R package RoundAndRound and PIHMgisR is used for this data processing and visulization.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The explanation of Bayesian Theorem in Statistics</title>
      <link>/zh/post/the-explanation-of-bayesian-theorem-in-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/post/the-explanation-of-bayesian-theorem-in-statistics/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;bayesian-probability&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bayesian probability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inference&lt;/strong&gt; Educated guessing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Bayes&#34;&gt;Thomas Bayes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; A nonconformist; two books, about theology and probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_inference&#34;&gt;Bayesian inference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Guessing the probability in the style of Bayes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayesian probability also known as evidential probability, is the process of adding &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prior_probability&#34;&gt;prior probability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to a hypothesis and adjusting that probability as new information becomes available. Unlike traditional frequentist probability which only accounts for the previous frequency of an event to predicate and outcome, the Bayesian model begins with an initial set of subjective assumptions (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prior_probability&#34;&gt;prior probability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) and adjusts them accordingly through trial and experimentation (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterior_probability&#34;&gt;posterior probability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). Instead of only rejecting or failing to reject a null hypothesis, Bayesian probability allows someone to quantify how much confidence they should have in a particular result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-are-bayesian-statistics-used-for&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are Bayesian Statistics Used for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While most machine learning models try to predict outcomes from large datasets, the Bayesian approach is helpful for several classes of problems that aren’t easily solved with other probability models. In particular:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Databases with few data points for reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Models with strong prior intuitions from pre-existing observations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data with high levels of uncertainty, or when it’s necessary to quantify the level of uncertainty across an entire model or compare different models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a model generates a null hypothesis but it’s necessary to claim something about the likelihood of the alternative hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beta_distribution&#34;&gt;Beta Distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;equations&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Equations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(H\)&lt;/span&gt; - Hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(E\)&lt;/span&gt; - Evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ P(H|E) = \frac {P(H)P(E|H)} { P(E)} \]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ P(A |B) = P(A) P(A|B) = P(B) P(B|A)\]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[P(A|B) = {P(A |B) }{P(A) }\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;reference&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deepai.org/machine-learning-glossary-and-terms/bayesian-statistics&#34;&gt;Bayesian Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5NMxiOGL39M&amp;amp;frags=pl%2Cwn&#34;&gt;How Bayes Theorem works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bobeo5kFz1g&#34;&gt;Bayesian statistics made (as) simple (as possible)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrologic modeling in project HYPERION</title>
      <link>/zh/research/hyperion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/research/hyperion/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-of-hyperion-i-class-fas-fa-external-link-alt-i-https-climate-ucdavis-edu-hyperion&#34;&gt;Introduction of HYPERION &lt;a href=&#34;https://climate.ucdavis.edu/hyperion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-external-link-alt&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of HYPERION is the development of a comprehensive regional hydroclimate data assessment capability focused on feature-specific metrics and stakeholder-relevant outcomes. The secondary objective of this proposal is to leverage this assessment capability to improve our ability to predict these outcomes, by identifying the process-level drivers of outcome biases and evaluating the most appropriate and efficient ways to couple climate models, hydrologic models, and models of human impacts.
&lt;img src=&#34;fig/hyperion.png&#34; alt=&#34;HYPERION logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks-in-hydrologic-modeling&#34;&gt;Tasks in hydrologic modeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a hydrologic modeling system for both the Sacramento watershed and several subcatchments.  Calculate key hydrological metrics, including stream flow, groundwater table, soil moisture, and snow pack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate the quality of the hydrologic model and identify potential issues related to its performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a statistical downscaling technique using both traditional statistical and machine learning methods that digests input to the hydrologic model and mimics the output of the model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine which input variables are most relevant for producing an accurate statistical model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Spatial Data&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Annual Precipitation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig/pihmdata.png&#34; alt=&#34;Data&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig/AnnualPRCP.png&#34; alt=&#34;Precipitation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sacramento-watershed&#34;&gt;Sacramento Watershed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sacramento River flows from Southern Oregon and to San Francisco Bay. Total drainage area is ~72000 km2. Elevation ranges from 0 to 4200m. The climate in SW is semi-arid hot Mediterranean. The spatial climatic characteristics are not only affected by latitude, terrain and snow coverage, but also by wind and ocean currents. Dramatic seasonal and annual climatic variations exist as well as large spatial heterogeneity. The mountains on the eastern and northern edges of the domain accumulate rain and snow which funnels into the groundwater of the whole watershed.  Annual precipitation ranges from 400 mm/year to 1500 mm/year, however extreme annual precipitation was more than 4000 mm/year in Northern mountainous area in 1983, and mean precipitation was only 270 mm/year from the 2013 extreme drought year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;fig/Animation.gif&#34;, width=400px&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Animation of spatial annual precipitation in Sacramento Watershed&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Monthly variation of precipitation in Sacramento Watershed&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Annual precipitation variation from 1979 to 2017 based on NLDAS data&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig/prcp_boxMonth.png&#34; alt=&#34;Data&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig/prcp_boxyr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Precipitation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;simulation-and-results&#34;&gt;Simulation and Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calibration of the PIHM model used the Covariance Matrix Adaptation Evolution Strategy (CMA-ES) (Hansen 2006,Auger 2005). The automatic CMA-ES calibration is robust and able to converge to global optimization with low computing cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;river-discharge&#34;&gt;River discharge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stream flow in the watershed follows the seasonal variation of precipitation. During drought years, the base flow from groundwater depletion contributes to the streamflow, and the excess infiltration replenishes ground water in wet seasons. For small watersheds in the Central Valley, such as catchment #9 where precipitation is less and the aquifer is thicker, the contribution from groundwater is small.
&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;fig/calib.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Calibration based on discharge of four subcatchments&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ground-water-variation&#34;&gt;Ground water variation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ground water near the river channel is shallower than the hill-slope. The spatial distribution pattern of ground water is controlled by topography, soil/geology characteristics and shape of the watershed. Steep slopes store less ground water than moderate slopes, because a steep hydraulic gradient on steep slopes drive the lateral groundwater flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig/GWmap.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig/gwd.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ground water spatial distribution&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Temporal fluctuation from 2000 to 2017.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ground water seasonal fluctuation follows the climatic variation. However, the seasonal variations in some catchments are relatively larger than others. The inter-annual variation in #5 sub-catchment is larger than seasonal variation. Although the annual precipitation trends in each sub-catchments are comparable, the trend in multiple-year changes of ground water table varies. This requires further analysis on water balance and the memory effect of ground water storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statement</title>
      <link>/zh/app/teachingstatement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/app/teachingstatement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love to train the next generation of hydrologists and environmental scientists. It is my belief that every student is capable of tasting the passion that I feel for hydrologic modeling by becoming a practitioner in the exploration of hydrological theories, researches and models.  I had three undergraduate sessions of teaching on Geography Information System years ago.
My teaching philosophy rests on three tenets: simplifying the complexity with mathematics, realizing ideas with programming, and integrating students in research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplifying the complexity with mathematics.&lt;/strong&gt;
 I invite my students to practice a series of steps: describing a natural problem, using physical law, making assumptions, making mathematical statement of the laws and solving math equations finally. As the fundamental procedure to think and solve the complex scientific problems, I will ask my students to practice and master this skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Realizing ideas with programming.&lt;/strong&gt;
We all have more ideas than solutions. Programming is one of the best options to realize or visualize your ideas about modeling, improvement and demonstration.  I teach students the steps and tips in computing algorithm as well as basic data structure, management, analysis and visualization in various programming language. For example, most of beginners are opt to use GUI tools to process and analysis spatial data processing and analysis, such as ArcGIS and QGIS. Actually, doing such tasks in programming, e.g. Matlab, R or Python, are so efficient that does not further understanding of theory and data only, but also inspires new ideas. After my class, the programming will be student’s first option to do complex computing or data processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrating students in research.&lt;/strong&gt;
Learning from practices is always better than listening in classroom, so I design the scientific problems in researches as on-class examples, solvable homework and projects for students. Due to compatibility of modeling methods, the problems from other fields are very welcomed in my class. For example, in Numeric Methods in Geosciences, one of class I plan to teach, the numeric methods can be used for various fields and topics, such as hydrology, mechanics, geology, limnology, etc., so students must think and practice the scientific problems in their own researches that fits the numeric methods discussed in class. In the final projects, students must pick a best-fit numeric method to solve doable problems in their fields. Of course, I will help them to define and solve the problems with tenet one and two mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find teaching students fulfilling because it offers an opportunity for me to engage and collaborate with the next generation of scholars and leaders. Besides, I also learn from my students. I offer a range of classes, from technical courses on hydrologic modeling, spatial data processing, data mining to seminars on urbanization and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The project to plot planets/objects in space and orbital movement.</title>
      <link>/zh/post/roundandround/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/post/roundandround/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I planed to write an R package and submit on CRAN, that can plot the planets orbiting in Solar System, or satellite/moon orbiting around earth. That package must plot the moving planets, the moon, moon phase and satellite in 2D or 3D canvas. In future, it may calculate the orbit based on orbit mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son loves the song “The wheels on the bus go round and round“, and he has an obsession on planets. He asks mommy play the solar system documentary every night when we ask him to brush his teeth.  So I decided to plot the moving planets in solar system for him with the scientific knowledge I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;photo.png&#34; alt=&#34;{{ include.description }}&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My son is obsessed by the planets and stars&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another motivation is from the Chinese lunar exploration, Chang-E 5 landing on far-side of the moon.  Lots of people discussed it and were fuddled on the rotation of moon and relation between the earth and the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I kept thinking the Chinese semi-lunar calendar for many years, I know the founder mental logic and algorithm of the calendar in my mind, but never scratched the equations and numbers in paper yet.  This calendar is determined by the moon phase and the position of the earth in orbit. Definitely the solver in papers are more rousted in my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see what I got, by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;Moon0.png&#34; alt=&#34;{{ include.description }}&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The idea of the Moon and the Sun are moving around the Earth, when we assume the earth is the center of system. The orbital period of the moon is 27.321 day, but the synodic period is 29.53 day, that because the sun moves 27.321/365.25 in its sun’s orbit when the moon moves in the moon’s orbit. It requires 2.2 days to let the sun and the moon to face-to-face again.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;Moon_year365.png&#34; alt=&#34;{{ include.description }}&#34; width=&#34;800&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The position of the Moon and the Sun in an earth year (365 day). The right legend shows the moon phase in 30 days. The concentric orbits are numbers of the moon periods.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The project to plot planets/objects in space and orbital movement.</title>
      <link>/zh/post/kids-ucd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/post/kids-ucd/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Motivation of the project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is fantastic program to teach the local kids and lead them into the discovering sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;fig/Classroom.jpg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt; Panoview of the Math&amp;Science classroom.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;week-02&#34;&gt;Week 02:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;fig/L03.jpg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Week 03: Jessica is writing students observation and discussion of plants in two different soils (Sperpentine and sandy loam). &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;week-05&#34;&gt;Week 05:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;fig/L05.jpg&#34; width=400px&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Week 05: The growth condition of their beans.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;fig/QA05.jpg&#34; width=300px&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Week 05: One question from students&#39; question box. Question: Why are my plants leaves sticky?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance programming</title>
      <link>/zh/teaching/class_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/teaching/class_programming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We Shape Our Tools, and Thereafter Our Tools Shape Us&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite-for-attendee&#34;&gt;Prerequisite for attendee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic programming knowledge, such as C/C++, Java, R, python, Matlab, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Textbooks&lt;/strong&gt;: None&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful sources&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yang, Daoqi. C++ and object-oriented numeric computing for scientists and engineers. Springer Science &amp;amp; Business Media, 2000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kernighan, Brian W., and Dennis M. Ritchie. The C programming language. 2006.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.163.2848&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Victor Shtern, Core C++ A Software Engineering Approach, Prentice Hall (2000) ISBN: 0130857297&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running Linux, 4th Edition, Welsh, Kaufman, Dalheimer, and Dawson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapman, Stephen J. JAVA for Engineers and Scientists. Prentice-Hall, Inc., 2003.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cornell, Gary, and Cay Stephen Horstmann. Core Java. SunSoft press, 1996.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghai, Ajit. &amp;ldquo;Facts and Fallacies of Software Engineering.&amp;rdquo; Software Quality Professional 5.3 (2003): 38.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mgnet.org/~douglas/Classes/na-sc/notes/Parallel%20Scientific%20Computing%20in%20C_plus_plus%20and%20MPI.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Karniadakis, George Em, George Karniadakis, and Robert M. Kirby II. Parallel scientific computing in C++ and MPI: a seamless approach to parallel algorithms and their implementation. Vol. 2. Cambridge University Press, 2003.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dept-info.labri.fr/~counilh/ens_parallelisme/mpi/pacheco_99.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pacheco, Peter. Parallel programming with MPI. Morgan Kaufmann, 1997.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two projects and 10 homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60% term project (30% per project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40% homework (4% each)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total 100%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-of-the-course&#34;&gt;Outline of the course&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The History and  Future of Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trends in Programming Languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilities: vi, emacs, dbx, make, cvs, and IDE&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brief Introduction to Software Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control and Arrays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pointers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structures, Classes, and Objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operator Overloading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input / Output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ vs. Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brief Discussion of Java, C#, and Objective-C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parallel Computing

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MPI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial and Geostatistical Analysis with R</title>
      <link>/zh/teaching/class_geospatialr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/teaching/class_geospatialr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We Shape Our Tools, and Thereafter Our Tools Shape Us&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite-for-attendee&#34;&gt;Prerequisite for attendee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preliminary knowledge and experience of spatial data
-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two projects and 10 homework.
40% term project (20% per project)
60% homework (6% each)
Total 100%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;content-of-course&#34;&gt;Content of course&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamental knowledge of spatial data and spatial analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R and Rstudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to find the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatial data format and manipulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatial data projection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of vector data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical and Geostatistical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numeric Methods in Hydrology</title>
      <link>/zh/teaching/class_fdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/teaching/class_fdm/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective to this class is to learn the steps involved in developing mathematical models for applied environmental/water resources problems, and using numerical methods to solve these mathematical models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become familiar with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explicit method,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implicit method,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linear/Non-Linear Partial Differential Equations (PDE), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numeric solutions for advection-dispersion equations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To write or use existing finite element and/or boundary element programs to analyze project scale problems. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite-for-attendee&#34;&gt;Prerequisite for attendee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;College calculus and algebra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groundwater hydraulics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic programming knowledge, such as C/C++, Java, R, python, Matlab, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Segerlind, L. J. Applied Finite Element Analysis. John Wiley and Sons, Inc., New York, NY (Reserve, Engineering Library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brebbia, C. A., J. C. F. Telles and L. C. Wrobel. Boundary Element Techniques. Springer Verlag, New York, NY (Reserve, Engineering Library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brebbia, C. A. and J. Dominguez. Boundary Elements&amp;ndash;An Introductory Course. McGraw Hill, New York, NY (Reserve, Engineering Library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kane, J. H. Boundary Element Analysis. Prentice Hall, Englewood Cliffs, NJ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gerald, C. F. and P. O. Wheatley. Applied Numerical Analysis. Addison Wesley, Reading, MA (Reserve, Engineering Library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two projects and 10 homeworks.
40% term project (20% per project)
60% homework (6% each)
Total 100%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Class&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Homework&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Taylor Series Hand writing the Taylor series, forward/backward/central derivative  equations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Euler/Heun/Runge-Kutta methods  Write code to compare the error of Euler, Heun and Runge-Kutta equations on two problems&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;class1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;class 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model simulated spatial distribution and the variation of ground water level in Sacramento Watershed, California from 1985 to 2017</title>
      <link>/zh/talk/agu2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/talk/agu2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;AnnualPRCP.png&#34; alt=&#34;{{ include.description }}&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Annual Precipitation (1985-2017) of Sacramento Watershed&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please stop by my poster, we can have a talk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numeric Methods in Hydrology</title>
      <link>/zh/class1/s01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/class1/s01/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1&#34;&gt;section 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2&#34;&gt;section 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>/zh/class1/hw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/class1/hw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This the introduction of the course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numeric Methods in Hydrology and Hdraulics</title>
      <link>/zh/class1/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/class1/homework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The homework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-1&#34;&gt;homework 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-2&#34;&gt;homework 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic hydrologic deployment and modeling</title>
      <link>/zh/research/mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/research/mint/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This project is the hydrologic modeling part of the project &lt;em&gt;Model Integration through Knowledge-Rich Data and Process Composition&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-of-project-i-class-fas-fa-external-link-alt-i-http-mint-project-info&#34;&gt;Introduction of project &lt;a href=&#34;http://mint-project.info&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-external-link-alt&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks-in-hydrologic-modeling&#34;&gt;Tasks in hydrologic modeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34;, width=800px&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The completed workflow of hydrologic modeling with PIHM model and national/global data services. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;fig/Animation.gif&#34;, width=800px&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Animation of flood plant in South Sudan from 2001 to 2017 based on FLDAS data. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;accomplishment-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Accomplishment of the project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keep updating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
